Alright so paddling out.
The one thing you want to be aware of is just where the surf is breaking.
You want to make sure to get past that surf as soon as possible.
If you get caught in there, like when that wave is coming in, you can kind of punch right through it if you're running right into it, otherwise you can kind of turn sideways and you're going to roll in the surf someplace, maybe lose some gear.
So what you've got to do is just paddle like crazy alternating strokes just one at a time.
There's nothing too hard about it.
This paddle here may be a little short for me since I'm a big tall guy.
This would be about six and a half feet long or so, seven feet.
So you might want to have a little bit longer paddle depending on how tall you are or how short you are.
So maybe talk to like a kayaking instructor, paddling instructor of some sort and see what they might recommend for your arm length and your size.
But again, just once you're, once you're paddled past that surf break you're kind of in the clear, there's things out there, it's safe and a little easier, but still watch out for the swell.
There might be some swell out there.
There might be some wind, and if there is wind kind of go towards that, go into it like, when, one rule of diving is that you always swim against the current so you can kind of swim back with it, the same with kayaking.
Go paddle into the wind so you can kind of return with the wind.
It'll make it a lot easier especially when you're tired at the end of it.